Episode 20
에피소드 20
Lady, be careful.
아가씨, 조심하세요.
Sure.
물론이죠.
Emotions disappear over time.
감정은 시간이 지나면서 사라진다.
Miss, what are you talking about?
아가씨, 무슨 말을 하는 겁니까?
It's nothing.
그것은 아무것도 아니다.
It seems like it suddenly got cold again.
갑자기 다시 추워진 것 같아요.
Mr. Hua, are you here?
Hua씨, 여기 계세요?
Are you going to look for your highness again?
다시 전하를 찾으러 가시나요?
Has Mr. Chi also come to see His Majesty?
치 선생님도 폐하를 만나러 오셨나요?
No, I came to see you.
아니요, 만나러 왔습니다.
Ah, that's right.
아, 그렇죠.
I will call you Miss Hua now.
이제 Miss Hua라고 불러야겠어요.
-You are divorced. -to let go!
-당신은 이혼했어요. -놓치다!
Miss Qi, be careful what you say!
미스 치, 말을 조심하세요!
to let go...
놓치다...
Why do you look at me like that?
왜 나를 그렇게 보는 거죠?
You have been lucky all your life.
당신은 평생 운이 좋았습니다.
Even if divorced
이혼했어도
There is no need to be too sad.
너무 슬퍼할 필요는 없습니다.
there are many people
많은 사람들이있다
Someone who is in a worse situation than you.
당신보다 더 나쁜 상황에 처해 있는 사람.
Qi Ruxin, how did I offend you?
Qi Ruxin, 내가 어떻게 당신을 화나게 했나요?
Life has been very easy so far.
지금까지는 너무 쉽게 살아왔습니다.
So I hate you to the core.
그래서 나는 당신을 핵심으로 싫어합니다.
however
그런데
I heard that your brother died.
네 형이 죽었다는 소식을 들었어.
-to let go! —Heaven is fair in the end.
-놓치다! —하늘은 결국 공평해요.
Please tell me one more thing about my sister.
내 동생에 대해 한 마디 더 해주세요
And I won't let you talk
그리고 당신이 말을 못하게 하도록 할게요
For the rest of your life.
남은 생애 동안.
What, you think you can scare me?
뭐야, 네가 나한테 겁을 줄 수 있을 것 같아?
Teacher Hua, please forgive my teacher.
화 선생님, 제 선생님을 용서해주세요.
assassins
암살자들
At the Mid-Autumn Festival banquet
중추절 연회에서
It put her in great fear.
그녀에게 큰 두려움을 안겨주었습니다.
She is still in shock.
그녀는 아직도 충격에 빠진 상태다
Therefore, you cannot think straight.
그러므로 똑바로 생각할 수 없습니다.
government.
정부.
Fahrenheit, have you come to see Your Highness?
화씨, 전하를 만나러 오셨나요?
to let go.
놓치다.
yes.
예.
I just came out of the study room.
방금 공부방에서 나왔는데
And this is where I met you.
그리고 여기서 당신을 만났습니다.
I think we have a connection.
아무래도 우리는 인연이 있는 것 같아요.
If you think about it, you weren't like that.
생각해보면 넌 그렇지 않았어
In the garden of bells for a long time.
오랫동안 종의 정원에.
great.
좋아요.
Fahrenheit, when you come to the bell garden again
화씨, 다시 종의 정원에 오면
please come visit my house
내 집에 놀러와주세요
I have someone to talk to
대화할 사람이 있어서
And don't feel so lonely
그리고 너무 외로워하지 마세요
I live here in Zhong's Garden.
여기 Zhong's Garden에 살고 있어요.
Aren't you kind!
당신은 친절하지 않습니까!
Sister Qi hasn’t been herself lately.
치 자매는 최근에 자신이 아니었습니다.
She has been saying inappropriate things.
그녀는 부적절한 말을 해왔습니다.
If she offended you in any way Miss Hua
만약 그녀가 어떤 식으로든 당신을 화나게 했다면 Miss Hua
I apologize on her behalf.
내가 그녀를 대신하여 사과드립니다.
I hope you don't take it to heart.
마음에 두지 않기를 바랍니다.
I won't.
나는하지 않을 것이다.
I tend to speak my mind.
나는 내 생각을 말하는 편이다.
some reasons
몇 가지 이유
It seemed like I liked you a lot
너를 많이 좋아하는 것 같았어
The moment I first saw you.
당신을 처음 본 순간.
You returned to the Hua family.
당신은 Hua 가족에게 돌아왔습니다.
And I regained my freedom.
그리고 자유를 되찾았습니다.
I'm really happy.
정말 기뻐요.
Now that I think about it, every time I see you
그러고 보니 널 볼 때마다
It felt somehow familiar.
왠지 친근감이 들더라구요.
Because the invitation has been extended
초대를 연장했으므로
Will I receive the glory?
영광을 받을 수 있을까요
Do you want to go to your house today?
오늘 네 집에 갈래?
I'm so happy!
정말 행복해요!
Miss Hua, we have never seen you.
Miss Hua, 우리는 당신을 본 적이 없습니다.
What have you been busy with?
무슨 일로 바빴나요?
Nothing special. It was just like that.
별거 없습니다. 그냥 그랬던 것뿐이야
I'm looking for my brother's killer.
내 동생의 살인자를 찾고 있어요.
Isn't this what Magistrate Wang should do?
이것이 왕 치안 판사가해야 할 일이 아닙니까?
Teacher Hua, why are you intervening?
Hua 선생님, 왜 개입하시나요?
prosecution investigation
검찰 수사
We are constrained by bureaucracy.
관료주의로 인해 제약을 받고 있습니다.
It's faster to do your own research.
직접 조사하는 것이 더 빠릅니다.
Plus I'm a target for assassins
게다가 나는 암살자의 표적이야
So I won't let him go that easily.
그래서 나는 그를 그렇게 쉽게 놓아주지 않을 것입니다.
Mr. Hua, you are so brave and wise.
Hua 씨, 당신은 정말 용감하고 현명해요.
Why wasn't she surprised
그녀는 왜 놀라지 않았나요
I was the target of an assassin?
내가 암살자의 표적이었다고?
Does she know something?
그녀가 뭔가 알고 있나요?
—Mr. Meng... —Why are you two together?
—멍 씨... —두 분은 왜 같이 계시나요?
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Lord.
주님.
I just happened to meet Teacher Hua.
방금 화 선생님을 우연히 만났습니다.
we were having a good time
우리는 즐거운 시간을 보내고 있었어
So I invited her to my house
그래서 나는 그녀를 내 집으로 초대했습니다
Continue.
계속하다.
In that case, please leave.
그 경우에는 떠나주세요.
I need to talk to Hua Qian.
Hua Qian과 얘기해야 해요.
Yes, Lord.
네, 주님.
Of course, it was decided that way.
당연하지, 그렇게 결정됐지
Miss Meng will be your wife.
Miss Meng이 당신의 아내가 될 것입니다.
I think he's polite
내가 보기엔 그 사람이 예의바른 것 같아
And have good manners.
그리고 예의가 좋다.
Nothing has been decided.
아무것도 결정되지 않았습니다.
But why does it make that sound...
그런데 왜 그런 소리가 나는지...
Are you jealous?
질투하는 거야?
I heard you were here.
당신이 여기 있었다고 들었습니다.
I put down what I was doing
하던 일을 내려놨다
And I came to see you.
그리고 당신을 만나러 왔습니다.
Why did you try to leave as soon as you saw me?
왜 나를 보자마자 떠나려고 했나요?
Lord, if you want to see me
주님, 저를 보고 싶으시다면
Why didn't I see you?
나는 왜 당신을 보지 못했어요?
During the two hours I was with His Majesty?
제가 전하와 함께 있었던 두 시간 동안?
You showed up only after Meng Yifei and I showed up.
당신은 Meng Yifei와 내가 나타난 후에야 나타났습니다.
We made plans to spend time together. why?
함께 시간을 보낼 계획을 세웠다. 왜?
What made you angry?
무엇이 당신을 화나게 만들었나요?
I was rude.
나는 무례했다.
Forgive me, Lord.
용서해주세요, 주님.
I'm going now.
저 이제가요.
Kian.
키안.
Recently, there have been a lot of things to take care of.
최근에는 챙겨야 할 일이 많아졌습니다.
I barely had time.
시간이 거의 안 나더라구요
I want to come and meet you today.
오늘 와서 만나려고요.
I thought I made myself clear that day.
나는 그날 내 자신을 분명히했다고 생각했습니다.
I've been waiting for you for a long time.
나는 오랫동안 당신을 기다리고 있었습니다.
It doesn't hurt to wait a little longer.
조금만 더 기다려도 문제가 되지 않습니다.
In the end you
결국 당신은
The daughter of the Hua family again.
다시 Hua 가문의 딸.
Lord.
주님.
You tend to oversimplify problems.
당신은 문제를 지나치게 단순화하는 경향이 있습니다.
things between you and me
너와 나 사이의 일들
It transcends our emotions.
우리의 감정을 초월합니다.
Does this mean he is the lord of the Zhong family?
종씨 가문의 영주라는 뜻인가요?
Are your thoughts simple?
생각이 단순하다?
You are interested in me too, right?
너도 나한테 관심 있는 거 맞지?
i know. You tend to worry a lot.
알아요. 당신은 걱정을 많이 하는 경향이 있습니다.
But what I said to you that day was sincere.
하지만 그날 내가 너에게 했던 말은 진심이었어.
You can come to me anytime.
언제든지 나에게 올 수 있습니다.
Like I said, it doesn't have to be that way.
내가 말했듯이, 그럴 필요는 없습니다.
I gave orders from the Tower of Star Reach.
나는 별 도달의 탑에서 명령을 내렸습니다.
Employees are involved in perfume making.
직원들이 향수 제조에 참여하고 있습니다.
It's on the first floor.
1층에 있어요.
No one is allowed on the 11th floor.
11층에는 누구도 들어갈 수 없습니다.
It's exclusive to you.
그것은 당신에게 독점적입니다.
You can go there.
거기로 가셔도 돼요
Whenever I feel like it.
기분이 좋을 때마다.
You can enjoy it quietly and peacefully without being disturbed.
방해받지 않고 조용하고 평화롭게 즐길 수 있습니다
When you are there.
당신이 거기 있을 때.
Thank you, but I'll decline.
고맙지 만 사양 할게.
It's on a high floor
높은 층에 있어요
I'm too tired to climb stairs.
계단 오르는 것도 너무 피곤해요.
I don't want to go there again.
나는 거기에 다시 가고 싶지 않습니다.
Look what the cat dragged in.
고양이가 무엇을 끌고 들어왔는지 보세요.
Lord, you rarely come here.
주님, 이곳에 오시는 경우는 드뭅니다.
Was there a conflict with Fahrenheit?
화씨랑 갈등이 있었나...
Butler Hua's daughter today?
오늘 버틀러 후아의 딸이요?
Lord, have you come to ask about this?
주님, 이것에 대해 물으러 오셨습니까?
The Hua family’s son has just passed away.
Hua 가문의 아들이 방금 세상을 떠났습니다.
So Hua Qian is now
그래서 Hua Qian은 지금
Butler Hua's only daughter.
버틀러 후아(Butler Hua)의 외동딸.
No matter what conflict you experienced
어떤 갈등을 겪었더라도
I hope you can give in to her.
나는 당신이 그녀에게 양보할 수 있기를 바랍니다.
You want to protect Hua Qian.
당신은 Hua Qian을 보호하고 싶습니다.
Why bother looking for excuses?
왜 굳이 변명거리를 찾는 걸까?
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
Judging by appearance
외모로 판단하면
you probably won't get what you want
당신은 아마 당신이 원하는 것을 얻을 수 없을 것입니다
like me.
나처럼.
I guess I'm not the only one.
나만 그런 건 아닌 것 같은데
Feeling miserable.
비참한 기분.
What do you know?
당신은 무엇을 알 수 있습니까?
i know what i need to know
나는 내가 알아야 할 것을 안다
And what I shouldn't know.
그리고 내가 몰라야 할 것.
why? Lord, will you silence me?
왜? 주님, 저를 침묵시키실 건가요?
Lord, please forgive her.
주님, 그녀를 용서해주세요.
The young lady was scared and scared.
아가씨는 겁이 나서 겁이 났어요
At the Mid-Autumn Festival banquet
중추절 연회에서
Therefore, she cannot think straight.
그러므로 그녀는 똑바로 생각할 수 없습니다.
watch her
그녀를 지켜보세요
And make sure she keeps her mouth shut.
그리고 그녀가 입을 다물고 있는지 확인하세요.
I have better things to do
나에겐 더 좋은 일이 있어
Rather than gossiping about people
사람에 대해 험담하는 것보다
It's funny not getting what you want.
원하는 것을 얻지 못하는 것은 재미있다.
Please let me experience this pleasure alone.
이 즐거움을 나 혼자만 맛보게 해주세요.
to let go!
놓치다!
Jong Si-woo...
종시우...
You can also become the lord of the Zong family
당신은 종 가문의 영주가 될 수도 있습니다
But you are just as pathetic as me
하지만 너도 나만큼 한심해
Because you can't get the woman you want.
원하는 여자를 얻을 수 없기 때문이다.
I am different from you.
나는 당신과 다릅니다.
Chen Yuan.
첸 위안.
Lord.
주님.
Send someone to watch over her.
그녀를 감시할 사람을 보내세요.
famous.
유명한.
Concubine Mu, I am your new maid Bansha.
후궁 무, 나는 당신의 새 하녀 반샤입니다.
The housekeeper sent it.
가정부가 보냈어요.
Is Jisoo not coming back?
지수는 안 돌아오나요?
The housekeeper said she couldn't contact Jisoo.
가사도우미가 지수랑 연락이 안 된다고 하더군요
A person who returns to visit his hometown.
고향을 방문하러 돌아온 사람.
He was afraid that you would not have enough maids.
그는 너희에게 하녀가 부족할까 봐 두려워하였느니라
So you sent me here to serve you.
그래서 당신을 섬기라고 나를 여기로 보냈습니다.
He'll keep sending people
그 사람은 계속 사람들을 보낼 거야
To find the index.
지수를 찾으러.
all right.
알겠어요.
Mr. Hwang said he had news.
황씨가 소식이 있다고 하더군요.
Teacher Hua, our men just sent news.
Hua 선생님, 우리 부하들이 방금 소식을 보냈습니다.
They saw a man dressed in black
그들은 검은 옷을 입은 남자를 보았어요
Sneaking out of the servant's residence.
종 거주지에서 몰래 빠져나가는 중.
Have you found the man's whereabouts?
그 남자의 행방은 찾았나요?
Yeah, that figure is gone.
응, 그 모습이 사라졌어
To a room on the second floor of the inn.
여관 2층에 있는 방으로.
in?
안에?
It's an inconspicuous inn.
눈에 띄지 않는 여관이다
A place where all kinds of people stay.
온갖 종류의 사람들이 머무는 곳.
after that?
그런 다음?
The guards following him were cautious.
그를 따라오던 경비병들은 조심스러웠다.
And I didn't confront that person.
그리고 그 사람과 대면하지 않았어
Instead they...
대신 그들은...
All Around Inn
올 어라운드 인
Sir, here is some wine. Enjoy!
선생님, 여기 와인이 있습니다. 즐기세요.
—Hello, innkeeper! -teacher.
—안녕하세요, 여관주인님! -선생님.
Are there any empty rooms?
빈 방이 있나요?
for a moment. I'll check it.
잠시만. 내가 체크해 볼게.
There is an empty room
빈 방이 있어요
It's on both the first and second floors.
1층과 2층에 모두 있어요.
Which floor do you prefer?
어느 층을 선호하시나요?
I want the leftmost room on the second floor.
2층 가장 왼쪽 방을 원해요.
Sir, what do you want?
선생님, 무엇을 원하시나요?
—A bottle of wine. -confident.
—와인 한 병. -확신하는.
Unfortunately, the room is already empty.
불행하게도 그 방은 이미 비어있습니다.
When will the room be available?
언제 방을 이용할 수 있나요?
I am used to staying in that room.
나는 그 방에 머무르는 데 익숙하다.
The guest in that room will leave tomorrow.
그 방에 있던 손님은 내일 떠날 거예요.
How about taking it to the room next door?
옆집 방으로 가져가는 게 어때요?
Can you get them to swap rooms with me?
그 사람들이 나와 방을 교환하도록 해줄 수 있나요?
I just want to stay in that room.
나는 그 방에만 머물고 싶다.
This doesn't seem appropriate.
이는 적절하지 않은 것 같습니다.
Those two guests were staying in that room.
그 두 손님은 그 방에 묵고 있었어요
for a few days.
며칠 동안.
Why did they stay so long?
그들은 왜 그렇게 오랫동안 머물렀는가?
Are you merchants?
상인들인가요?
I do not know.
모르겠습니다.
Probably tourists from somewhere.
아마 어딘가에서 온 관광객들이겠지
Because they have been inquiring
그들이 문의해 왔기 때문에
Donghuang Mountain in the past few days.
지난 며칠 동안 동황산.
OK. You know what to do.
괜찮은. 넌 뭘해야 할 지 알 잖아.
all right!
알았어요!
Donghuang Mountain?
동황산?
i was born again
나는 다시 태어났다
But his escape route remains the same.
하지만 그의 탈출 경로는 동일하게 유지됩니다.
Are you sure about tomorrow?
내일이 확실해요?
Has our guard been found?
우리 경비원이 발견됐나요?
Obtaining this information was not easy.
이 정보를 얻는 것은 쉽지 않았습니다.
What does the other person think?
상대방이 생각하는가?
Did they intentionally leak this information to us?
의도적으로 이 정보를 우리에게 유출한 걸까요?
I don't think so.
나는 그렇게 생각하지 않습니다.
But just in case
하지만 혹시라도
Guards chasing the man in black
검은옷의 남자를 추적한 경비병들
We broke up on purpose.
일부러 헤어졌습니다.
One person went to the counter to make an inquiry.
한 명은 문의를 하러 카운터로 갔습니다.
while the other one sits in the lobby
다른 한 명은 로비에 앉아 있는 동안
And I pretended to be a guest.
그리고 손님인 척 했어요
To observe the surroundings.
주변을 관찰하기 위해.
Nothing seemed normal
아무것도 평범해 보이지 않았어
So I don't think it's a trap.
그래서 나는 그것이 함정이라고 생각하지 않습니다.
The man in black was careless
검은옷의 남자는 부주의했다
And didn't realize he was being followed.
그리고 그가 미행되고 있다는 사실을 깨닫지 못했습니다.
imprudent?
경솔한?
Is it really that simple?
정말 그렇게 간단합니까?
are you okay.
괜찮아요.
I think it would be better not to miss the opportunity.
기회를 놓치지 않는 게 좋을 것 같아요.
Worst case scenario, I'll wait there every day.
최악의 경우 매일 거기서 기다리겠습니다.
Now, go get some more men.
자, 가서 남자들을 더 모아라
And take as many people with you as possible.
그리고 최대한 많은 사람을 데리고 가세요
And he placed an ambush at the foot of the mountain.
그리고 산기슭에 매복병을 두었습니다.
Move in batches.
일괄적으로 이동합니다.
Remember to keep a low profile.
낮은 프로필을 유지하는 것을 잊지 마십시오.
Be discreet when you go there.
거기로 갈 때 눈에 띄지 않게 하세요.
I will go there tomorrow.
나는 내일 거기에 갈 것이다.
I took note, Miss.
참고했어요, 미스.
Have you prepared the carriage?
마차는 준비하셨나요?
Let's hurry.
서두르자.
Get it.
그것을 얻으십시오.
Miss Hua, we are doing exciting things.
Miss Hua, 우리는 신나는 일을 하고 있어요.
i am afraid
나는 두려워
It will get the attention of soldiers.
군인들의 관심을 끌 것입니다.
This is my intention.
이것이 나의 의도이다.
Then the mastermind will be revealed.
그러면 주모자가 드러날 것입니다.
well...
잘...
are you okay.
괜찮아요.
He won't dare ask for help
그는 감히 도움을 청하지 못할 것이다
When martial law was imposed on the city.
도시에 계엄령이 내려졌을 때.
Teacher, don't worry about me.
선생님, 제 걱정은 마세요.
Just run!
그냥 달려라!
Do your worst, Hua Qian.
최악의 일을 해라, Hua Qian.
Are you seriously planning to kill me?
진심으로 나를 죽일 셈이냐?
Do you think you can escape punishment?
처벌을 면할 수 있다고 생각하시나요?
After killing me?
나를 죽인 후?
You are just an escaped slave.
당신은 단지 탈출한 노예일 뿐입니다.
So what if I kill you?
그럼 내가 당신을 죽인다면 어떨까요?
Don't play games with me.
나랑 게임하지 마세요.
You clearly know who I am.
당신은 내가 누구인지 분명히 알고 있습니다.
me too? Then who are you?
나도요? 그러면 당신은 누구입니까?
I have the courage to arrest you
난 당신을 체포할 용기가 있어요
But do you dare ask for help?
그런데 감히 도움을 청할 수 있나요?
I'll leave it to you to decide if you want
당신이 원하는지 결정하는 것은 당신에게 맡길 것입니다
I admit that I have caused harm to the Hua family.
Hua 가족에게 해를 끼쳤다는 것을 인정합니다.
If you surrender now
지금 항복한다면
I'll tell the guards to stop.
경비병들한테 그만하라고 말할게
And we can have a discussion.
그리고 우리는 토론을 할 수 있습니다.
Otherwise we will fight until you die.
그렇지 않으면 우리는 당신이 죽을 때까지 싸울 것입니다.
master...
주인...
don't do it
하지 않다.
It’s been a long time, junior Woo.
오랜만이군요, 우후배님.
How did you know I would come here?
내가 여기 올 줄 어떻게 알았어?
You told me that too.
당신도 나한테 그렇게 말했잖아요.
nonsense!
무의미한 말!
I'm leaving Hwangcheong tomorrow.
내일 황청을 떠날 거예요
Via Donghuang Mountain pass.
동황산(Donghuang Mountain) 고개를 경유합니다.
Please go and expose me as quickly as possible.
최대한 빨리 가서 나를 폭로해 주세요.
Let's see who will believe a fugitive like you.
너 같은 도망자를 누가 믿을지 보자.
your dull heart
둔한 너의 마음
You won't be able to figure this out.
이것을 알아낼 수 없을 것입니다.
Throw it in the carriage behind me
내 뒤에 있는 마차에 던져줘
And take it back.
그리고 다시 가져가세요.
Go tomorrow and spread the word.
내일 가서 소문을 퍼뜨려라.
I want everyone in Huangcheng
나는 Huangcheng의 모든 사람을 원합니다
To hear about this.
이것에 대해 듣기 위해.
The Hua family has put in a lot of effort.
Hua 가족은 많은 노력을 기울였습니다.
And got caught...
그리고 잡혔다...
escaped slave.
탈출한 노예.
I took note, Miss.
참고했어요, 미스.
How dare you arrest me!
감히 나를 체포하다니!
Aren’t you afraid of being in danger?
위험에 빠질까 두렵지 않니?
long term cooperation
장기적인 협력
Between the Zhong family and the Wu family?
Zhong 가족과 Wu 가족 사이에?
Why didn't you say this?
왜 이런 말을 안 했어?
When you get arrested?
체포됐을 때?
King Wu appears in Huangcheng.
우왕(吳君)이 황성(黃成)에 나타나다
uninvited
초대받지 않은
Even though the study tour is over.
스터디 투어가 끝났음에도 불구하고.
If your identity is exposed
본인의 신원이 노출된 경우
Then won't the Wu family's conspiracy be revealed?
그러면 우 가문의 음모도 드러나지 않을까요?
Stealing a perfume formula?
향수 공식을 훔친 것?
when that happens
그런 일이 일어날 때
Will there still be collaborations?
아직도 콜라보레이션이 있을까
Between the Zhong family and the Wu family?
Zhong 가족과 Wu 가족 사이에?
Who said I wanted to steal?
누가 내가 훔치고 싶다고 했어?
Perfume formula?
향수 공식?
I'm just...
난 그냥...
We stayed in Huangcheng for a few more days.
며칠 더 황성(Huangcheng)에 머물렀습니다.
Is that true?
그게 사실인가요?
Then explain why you need it.
그런 다음 왜 필요한지 설명하십시오.
Lie down in Hwangseong (黃成).
황성(黃成)에 눕는다.
Or should I hand you over to the magistrate?
아니면 당신을 치안 판사에게 넘겨야 할까요?
For investigation?
조사를 위해?
Hua Chen.
화첸.
I had no idea how ruthless you could be.
나는 당신이 얼마나 무자비할 수 있는지 몰랐습니다.
Am I ruthless?
내가 무자비하다고?
You committed a banquet massacre.
당신은 연회 학살을 자행했습니다.
Did you expect no one to retaliate?
아무도 보복하지 않을 거라고 예상했나요?
how did you know?
어떻게 알았어?
This wound appears to be almost completely healed.
이 상처는 거의 아물은 것 같습니다.
Why don't you explain how you got hurt?
어떻게 다쳤는지 설명하지 그래?
I think it's someone I fought with
같이 싸운 사람인 것 같아
You were the magician of the valley.
계곡의 화용주가 바로 당신이었습니다.
I asked how you knew that.
나는 당신이 그것을 어떻게 알았는지 물었습니다.
How did I know about it?
나는 그것에 대해 어떻게 알았습니까?
I would say you have given up on yourself.
나는 당신이 자신을 포기했다고 말하고 싶습니다.
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
If it weren't for someone I knew
내가 아는 사람이 아니었다면
That person probably didn't know that
그 사람은 그걸 몰랐을 텐데
Hua Rongzhou was looking for me in the valley.
Hua Rongzhou가 계곡에서 나를 찾고있었습니다.
And even told him which way to go.
그리고 그에게 어느 길로 가야 할지 말해 주기까지 했습니다.
Or maybe I should say it like this
아니면 아마도 이렇게 말해야 할 것 같아요
Mu Yao betrayed you?
무야오가 당신을 배신했다고요?
I don't know what you're talking about.
무슨 말을 하는지 모르겠어요.
You are a dedicated person. It's really touching.
당신은 헌신적인 사람이에요. 정말 감동적이네요.
I wonder if Muyao will move
무야오가 움직일지 궁금해
What if she knows?
만약 그녀가 알고 있다면?
What gift do you think I should give her?
내가 그녀에게 어떤 선물을 주어야 한다고 생각하나요?
So I can tell that that person is you?
그럼 그 사람이 바로 당신인 걸 알 수 있게요?
finger?
손가락?
eye?
눈?
Or is it just one ear?
아니면 한쪽 귀인가요?
You evil woman!
이 사악한 여자야!
Why not the tongue?
혀는 왜 안되나요?
Anyway, nothing good comes out of my mouth.
어쨌든 입에서 좋은 말이 나오지 않습니다.
Just take it from me.
그냥 나한테 가져가.
I am doing just that.
나는 바로 그 일을 하고 있다.
What I want to cut off is your tongue
잘라버리고 싶은 건 네 혀야
And your fingers too.
그리고 당신의 손가락도요.
It's your eyes that I want to pierce through.
내가 꿰뚫고 싶은 것도 당신의 눈이에요.
Didn't we say we'd have a discussion?
우리가 토론을 하자고 하지 않았나요?
What if I surrender?
내가 항복한다면?
Did you give me a chance to talk?
나에게 말할 기회를 주었나요?
The person who killed your brother was not one of my men.
네 동생을 죽인 사람은 내 부하 중 한 사람이 아니야
At the banquet.
연회에서.
So who is it?
그렇다면 누구입니까?
I do not know either.
나도 모른다.
Are you talking?
당신은 말하고 있습니까?
Was there another group of assassins?
또 다른 암살자 그룹이 있었나요?
yes.
예.
Why did you pretend to be from the Ge clan?
왜 Ge씨족 행세를 했나
To assassinate me?
암살을 하려고?
Because you know how I feel about you.
내가 당신에 대해 어떻게 생각하는지 당신이 알기 때문에
do you trust me
당신은 날 믿어?
What do you believe you will do?
당신이 무엇을 할 것이라고 믿으십니까?
I'll take you there.
내가 데려다 줄게.
Why should I leave with you?
내가 왜 당신과 함께 떠나야 합니까?
Because you are the only person I love.
당신은 내가 사랑하는 유일한 사람이기 때문입니다.
So what? you like me
그래서 뭐? 너는 나를 좋아해
Then do I have to go with you?
그럼 나도 꼭 같이 가야 해?
Would you like to share?
공유하시겠습니까?
Is your husband with Hua Qian?
당신의 남편은 Hua Qian과 함께 있나요?
shut up!
입 다물어!
Don't say you didn't notice
눈치채지 못했다고 말하지 마세요
Jong Ye-ran started it.
종예란이 시작했다고
He develops feelings for Hua Qian.
Hua Qian에 대한 감정을 가지게됩니다.
He initially did not agree to divorce Hua Qian.
그는 처음에는 Hua Qian과의 이혼에 동의하지 않았습니다.
'Cause he knew you would
왜냐면 그 사람은 네가 그럴 줄 알았거든
Take down Hua Qian.
Hua Qian을 쓰러뜨려라.
He wanted to take advantage of his position
그는 자신의 지위를 이용하고 싶었습니다
To protect Hua Qian
Hua Qian을 보호하기 위해
From the involvement of the Hua family.
Hua 가족의 연루에서.
Later he changed his mind.
나중에 그는 마음을 바꾸었다.
I agreed to divorce Hua Qian.
Hua Qian과 이혼하기로 합의했습니다.
It wasn't because of you
너 때문이 아니었어
But because Hua Qian insisted,
하지만 Hua Qian이 고집했기 때문에
divorce
이혼하다
So he granted her wish.
그래서 그는 그녀의 소원을 들어주었다.
If you still have doubts
아직도 의심이 든다면
How about we make a bet?
우리 내기하는 게 어때?
Between you and Hua Qian
당신과 Hua Qian 사이
Let's see who he will choose.
그가 누구를 선택할지 봅시다.
OK.
괜찮은.
What should I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
I understand the reason without you having to say it.
말하지 않아도 이유는 알겠다.
Anyway you're in my hands
어쨌든 넌 내 손 안에 있어
So let's see if Mu Yao will come looking for you.
그러니 Mu Yao가 당신을 찾으러 올지 봅시다.
—Leave her alone! —Why should I?
—그녀를 내버려두세요! —내가 왜 그래야 합니까?
There is nothing between Mu Yao and me.
Mu Yao와 나 사이에는 아무것도 없습니다.
What happens to me has nothing to do with her.
나에게 일어나는 일은 그녀와 관련이 없습니다.
When I see you.
당신을 보면.
You are a junior lord
당신은 후배 영주입니다
One of the largest hub suppliers.
최대 허브 공급업체 중 하나입니다.
you need to focus on your business
당신은 당신의 사업에 집중해야합니다
Instead of doing something stupid.
어리석은 짓을 하는 대신.
Because of you, the Wu family will decline.
당신 때문에 Wu 가족이 쇠퇴할 것입니다.
Besides, it doesn't matter what happened
게다가 무슨 일이 일어났든 상관없어
Between you two.
너희 둘 사이.
Do you expect me to be moved by your devotion?
내가 당신의 헌신에 감동받기를 기대하시나요?
And will you help me keep you two together?
그리고 너희 둘이 함께 있도록 도와줄래?
So you knew why.
그래서 당신은 그 이유를 알고 있었습니다.
Is there any reason to ask again?
굳이 다시 물어볼 이유가 있나요?
So what if I knew?
그럼 내가 알면 어떨까?
If you ask her, there will be room for negotiation.
그녀에게 물어보면 협상할 여지가 생긴다.
however
그런데
Throw out the other man.
다른 남자를 내쫓아라.
We won't waste any medication on him.
우리는 그에게 약을 낭비하지 않을 것입니다.
He's not worth it.
그는 그럴 가치가 없습니다.
You are truly a changed person.
당신은 정말로 변화된 사람입니다.
No wonder she sensed danger.
그녀가 위험을 감지한 것도 당연합니다.
I shouldn't have made that bet.
나는 그런 내기를 하지 말았어야 했다.
I could never win.
나는 결코 이길 수 없었습니다.
men! An intruder has appeared at Hua Residence!
남자들! 후아 레지던스에 침입자가 나타났다!
Go there! go!
거기 가서! 가다!
-Have you seen him? -no.
-그 사람 봤었 어? -아니요.
Let's go over there. hurry!
저쪽으로 가자. 서두르다!
Last night, someone broke into Hua Residence.
어젯밤 누군가 Hua Residence에 침입했습니다.
Teacher Hua, are you okay here?
Hua 선생님, 여기 괜찮으세요?
Did you catch him?
그를 잡았나요?
no.
아니요.
what?
무엇?
The guards in this house are useless.
이 집의 경비원은 쓸모가 없습니다.
They couldn't even catch random intruders.
그들은 무작위 침입자조차 잡을 수 없었습니다.
How about this?
이건 어때?
Go tell your dad I'm anxious
가서 아버지한테 내가 불안하다고 전해줘
Because of the intruder
침입자 때문에
And I don't think I can sleep well
그리고 나 잠을 잘 못 잘 것 같아
A few days later.
며칠 후.
So let's borrow some guards.
그러니 경비병 몇 명을 빌려야지
From Magistrate King
왕 치안판사로부터
About a month and a half.
한 달 반 정도.
famous. I will inform Butler Hua immediately.
유명한. 즉시 버틀러 후아에게 알릴게요.
Your injuries healed in time
당신의 부상은 제때에 치유되었습니다
And you could help with that.
그리고 당신은 그 일을 도와줄 수 있었어요.
Rest assured, lady.
안심하세요, 아가씨.
No one knows what happened last night.
어젯밤에 무슨 일이 일어났는지 아무도 모릅니다.
I have no doubts about your agility.
나는 당신의 민첩성에 대해 의심의 여지가 없습니다.
Magistrate King's bodyguards
왕 치안판사 경호원들
It belongs to the government.
정부에 속해 있습니다.
Even if you have no skills
실력이 없더라도
They are not just security guards at Hua Residence.
그들은 단순한 Hua Residence의 경비원이 아닙니다.
Who wants to spy on Hua Residence?
Hua Residence를 염탐하려는 사람은 누구입니까?
You'll think twice.
두 번 생각할 것입니다.
You look pretty in this color.
이 색을 입으니 예뻐 보이네요.
Thank you for coming.
와주셔서 감사합니다.
Mr. Hwang, there is no need to be so polite.
황 씨, 그렇게 예의바르게 행동할 필요는 없어요.
Please come this way.
이쪽으로 오십시오.
Jong Residence
종 레지던스
Is there anyone there?
거기 누구 있어요?
I let you go.
나는 당신을 놓아주었습니다.
Why did you come back?
왜 돌아왔나요?
Concubine Mu Huacheon has captured my master.
후궁 무화천이 나의 주인을 사로잡았느니라.
Are you an escaped slave?
탈출한 노예인가
That person claimed he caught them?
그 사람이 자신이 붙잡았다고 주장했다고요?
yes.
예.
Guard Cang escaped.
Guard Cang은 탈출했습니다.
He sent us information
그는 우리에게 정보를 보냈습니다
So we're confident that's true.
그래서 우리는 그것이 사실이라고 확신합니다.
Your master’s whereabouts were a secret.
네 주인의 행방은 비밀이었다.
Even I didn't know.
나조차도 몰랐다.
How did Hua Qian know?
Hua Qian은 어떻게 알았나요?
We don't know either.
우리도 모릅니다.
Why did you come to see me today?
오늘 왜 나를 만나러 왔나요?
Hua Residence is currently
Hua Residence는 현재
Bodyguards are watching.
경호원들이 감시하고 있다.
If we come to save him
우리가 그를 구하러 들이닥친다면
We can also warn them.
우리는 그들에게 경고할 수도 있습니다.
so?
그래서?
Master told us repeatedly
스승님은 우리에게 반복해서 말씀하셨습니다
so as not to disturb you
당신을 방해하지 않도록
But the problem is urgent.
그런데 문제가 급해요.
Mu-cheop, please save our master.
무첩님, 우리 주인님을 구해주세요.
I have brought it to your master.
내가 그것을 네 주인에게 가져왔느니라.
are you okay.
괜찮아요.
I won't corner him.
나는 그를 궁지에 몰아넣지 않을 것이다.
Go back now.
지금 돌아가세요.
Trust me...
저를 믿으세요...
Bring your master to you in one piece.
당신의 주인을 한 조각으로 당신에게 데려오십시오.
Thank you, Muchup!
고마워요, 무첩님!
Muyao...
무야오...
What caused you to become someone you despise?
당신이 경멸하는 사람이 된 이유는 무엇입니까?
to let go.
놓치다.
Magistrate Wang's guards are here.
왕 치안판사 경호원들이 여기에 왔어요
For almost a week.
거의 일주일 동안.
And it was quite peaceful here.
그리고 여기는 꽤 평화로웠어요.
I heard it from Mr. Hwang.
황씨한테 들었어
They were talking about leaving.
그들이 떠나는 것에 대해 이야기하고 있었다고.
This is unexpected.
이것은 예상치 못한 일입니다.
It was amazing how patient they were.
그들이 얼마나 인내심을 갖고 있는지 놀라웠습니다.
Miss, have you figured out what to do next?
아가씨, 다음에 무엇을 해야 할지 알아냈나요?
to let go.
놓치다.
Miss Meng sent another invitation.
Miss Meng이 또 다른 초대장을 보냈습니다.
Meng Yi Fei
멍이페이
Miss, are you still going?
아가씨, 아직도 가시나요?
You're refusing that person's invitation?
그 사람의 초대를 거절한다고요?
Anyway, I have nothing to do.
어쨌든 나는 할 일이 없습니다.
Let's go out for a walk.
산책하러 나가자.
Mr. Hua, please take a seat.
Hua 씨, 자리에 앉으세요.
Come and try this tea.
와서 이 차를 맛보세요.
This is Dragon Musk Tea.
드래곤 머스크 티 입니다
My father brought it from the south for me.
내 아버지가 나를 위해 남쪽에서 가져온 것입니다.
I'm thankful that he thought of me.
그 사람이 나를 생각해줘서 고마워요
Despite being immersed in work.
일에 몰두하고 있음에도 불구하고.
I don't offer it to just anyone.
나는 그것을 누구에게나 제공하지 않습니다.
I am so lucky.
나는 정말 운이 좋다.
After you left the servant's garden that day
그날 당신이 종의 정원을 떠난 후
I hoped we could talk again.
나는 우리가 다시 이야기할 수 있기를 바랐다.
Unfortunately, you keep rejecting my invitations.
안타깝게도 당신은 내 초대를 계속 거절했어요
He said he was busy.
바쁘다고 하더군요.
Today, my wish finally came true.
오늘 드디어 소원을 이루었습니다.
I'm sorry, Mr. Meng.
죄송해요, 멩 선생님.
I've been a bit busy lately.
최근에는 좀 바빴어요.
really?
정말?
I thought it was an excuse.
나는 그것이 핑계라고 생각했다.
So, what's keeping you busy?
그래서, 당신은 무엇 때문에 바쁘나요?
Coincidentally
우연히도
I caught a fugitive a few days ago.
며칠 전에 도망자를 잡았어요
When I was looking for an escaped slave.
내가 탈출한 노예를 찾고 있었을 때.
And it turns out the fugitive was involved
그리고 그 도망자가 연루된 것으로 밝혀졌습니다
In the banquet assassination case
연회 암살 사건에서
a few days ago.
며칠 전.
So I was busy.
그래서 나는 바빴다.
Trying to find out what he knows.
그가 무엇을 알고 있는지 알아내려고 노력 중입니다.
great.
좋아요.
I hope the murderer is punished.
살인범은 꼭 처벌받길 바랍니다
And get the punishment you deserve.
그리고 그에 합당한 벌을 받으십시오.
I hope so too, Mr. Meng.
저도 그랬으면 좋겠습니다, 멩 선생님.
You rarely come here.
여기 오시는 경우는 드뭅니다.
We should have a good time.
우리는 즐거운 시간을 보내야합니다.
People come and go to the Bell Garden
사람들은 종의 정원에 오고 갑니다
But I rarely meet people like you
하지만 난 너 같은 사람을 거의 만나지 않아
People I can chat with.
내가 채팅할 수 있는 사람.
I thought you and Miss Qi were very close?
당신과 미스 치(Miss Qi)가 아주 친하다고 생각했어요?
These days, Mr. Chi seems to have become a different person.
요즘 치씨는 다른 사람이 된 것 같다.
But she won't tell me what happened.
하지만 그녀는 무슨 일이 있었는지 나에게 말하지 않을 것입니다.
That guy must have been hit hard.
그 사람은 분명 큰 타격을 받았을 거야
That's what got her in this state.
그것이 그녀를 이런 상태로 만들었습니다.
Actually, Mr. Chi has a sharp tongue.
사실 치씨는 혀가 날카로운 편이다
And her words may be harsh
그리고 그녀의 말이 가혹할 수도 있습니다
But she means well.
하지만 그녀는 좋은 뜻을 갖고 있어요.
Sometimes she feels more guilty.
때때로 그녀는 죄책감을 더 많이 느낀다.
towards someone
누군가를 향해
Her words are even harsher.
그녀의 말은 더욱 가혹합니다.
Feeling guilty?
죄책감이 드는?
I was just citing an example.
나는 단지 예를 인용하고 있었을 뿐이다.
How about you?
당신은 어때요?
I don't know what's special about me
나한테 특별한 게 뭔지 모르겠어
Then you will think of me differently.
그러면 당신은 나를 다르게 생각하게 됩니다.
I can see it clearly even if others can't.
다른 사람들이 볼 수 없어도 나는 그것을 분명히 볼 수 있습니다.
I felt you set yourself apart from the rest
나는 당신이 나머지 사람들과 차별화되는 것을 느꼈습니다
Since I first saw you.
당신을 처음 본 이후로.
And you escaped assassination twice.
그리고 당신은 두 번이나 암살을 면했습니다.
After bad luck, good luck follows.
불운 뒤에는 행운이 따른다.
My father is the butler of the head family.
나의 아버지는 종가의 집사이다.
business in the south
남쪽에서의 사업
When your father was a butler
네 아버지가 집사일 때
From the Zhong family.
종씨 가문 출신.
If we can take care of each other in the future
앞으로 우리가 서로를 보살필 수 있다면
Then we are standing in the garden of servants
그러면 종의 정원에 우리가 서 있는 것은
It is strengthened.
강화됩니다.
Teacher Meng, I don’t understand.
멩 선생님, 이해가 안 돼요
What you are saying.
당신이 말하는 것.
You are a smart girl.
당신은 똑똑한 소녀입니다.
Surely you understand what I am saying.
확실히 당신은 내가 말하는 것을 이해합니다.
The Lord has feelings for you.
주님은 당신에 대한 감정을 가지고 계십니다.
I know because I have been there too.
저도 거기 가본 적이 있어서 압니다.
There will be many opportunities
기회는 많을 것이다
A place where you and I can work together.
너와 내가 함께 일할 수 있는 곳.
Teacher Meng, don’t make fun of me.
멩 선생님, 저를 놀리지 마세요.
OK...
괜찮은...
I won't tease you any more.
나는 더 이상 당신을 놀리지 않을 것입니다.
In any case, we have a long way to go before us.
어쨌든 우리 앞에는 갈 길이 멀다.
Let's have tea.
차를 마시자.
great.
좋아요.
Sis Hua, come here when you have time.
Sis Hua, 시간이 나면 여기로 오세요.
It's dirty. Just throw it away.
더럽습니다. 그냥 버리세요.
Yes, lady.
네, 아가씨.
Master, I saw where Concubine Wu was going.
스승님, 무후궁이 어디로 가는지 보았습니다.
She seemed to be going to Hua Residence.
그녀는 Hua Residence에가는 것 같았습니다.
Magistrate King's bodyguards
왕 치안판사 경호원들
It's still at Hua Residence.
아직 Hua Residence에 있어요.
It would be unwise
그것은 현명하지 못한 일이 될 것이다
Concubine Mu will go there alone.
첩 무가 혼자 거기에 가겠다.
with her agility
그녀의 민첩함으로
Avoiding those guards isn't a problem.
그 경비병을 피하는 것은 문제가 되지 않습니다.
I think Concubine Wu will go there.
내 생각엔 무후궁이 거기로 갈 것 같아
To meet the mistress... I mean, Miss Hua.
여주인을 만나러... 제 말은, Miss Hua입니다.
Master, are you really going to ignore me?
주인님, 정말 무시하실 겁니까?
Why should I care?
내가 왜 관심을 가져야 합니까?
It's between them.
그것은 그들 사이에 있습니다.
No one else should intervene.
다른 사람이 개입해서는 안 됩니다.
but...
하지만...
When Hua Qian left
Hua Qian이 떠났을 때
She only took her belongings.
그녀는 소지품만 가져갔습니다.
She didn't play zither or chess.
그녀는 치터나 체스를 안 댔어요
The ink brush and inkstone I gave her.
내가 그녀에게 준 먹붓과 벼루.
When you have time, send it to her.
시간이 나면 그녀에게 보내세요.
Okay, Master.
알았습니다, 마스터.
Consider it over.
끝났다고 생각해 보세요.
to let go...
놓치다...
Was he embarrassed because I didn't take him?
내가 데려가지 않아서 당황한 걸까
In the garden of bells?
종의 정원에?
Go talk to the chef
셰프에게 가서 말해요
I'm going to make a few more dishes for dinner.
저녁으로 몇 가지 요리를 더 만들려고요.
We will eat together.
우리는 함께 먹을 거예요.
Yes, lady.
네, 아가씨.
Teacher, Mu Yao is here.
선생님, Mu Yao가 여기 있습니다.
How did it feel to overcome the wall?
벽을 넘는 기분은 어땠나요?
Where is he?
그는 어디에 있나요?
WHO?
WHO?
don't do anything stupid to me
나한테 바보같은 짓은 하지 마
Why are you in a hurry?
왜 급해요?
you came here uninvited
당신은 초대받지 않고 여기에 왔습니다
And I just got back.
그리고 방금 돌아왔어.
Can I drink some water and take a breather?
물 좀 마시고 숨 좀 쉬면 안 될까요?
You let his guards go on purpose.
당신은 고의로 그의 경비병을 풀어주었습니다.
You wanted him to tell me, right?
당신은 그 사람이 나에게 알려 주기를 바랐죠, 그렇죠?
I don't have time to play games with you.
나는 당신과 게임을 할 시간이 없습니다.
I have come as you wish.
나는 당신이 원하는 대로 왔습니다.
Can you let him go now?
이제 그를 놓아줄 수 있나요?
How did that cup make you feel?
그 컵이 당신에게 어떤 기분을 상하게 했나요?
Where did you pick it up?
어디서 픽업하셨나요?
Bad habit of breaking cups?
컵 깨는 나쁜 버릇?
You have to give up your habits.
습관을 버려야 합니다.
Hua Chen!
화첸!
since you know that
당신이 그걸 알고부터
You came here to ask me for help.
당신은 나에게 도움을 청하러 여기 왔습니다
Shouldn't you be more polite?
좀 더 예의바르게 행동해야 하지 않나?
I am here now.
나는 지금 여기에 있다.
Do whatever you want with me.
나한테 원하는 대로 해주세요.
Just send it to me. He has nothing to do with this.
그냥 보내주세요. 그는 이것과 아무 관련이 없습니다.
He has nothing to do with this?
그 사람은 이 일과 아무 관련이 없다고요?
Mu Yao, your cheek
Mu Yao, 너의 뺨
To get that out there.
그 말을 꺼내려고.
Are you saying Wu Shuomo wasn't involved?
Wu Shuomo가 관여하지 않았다는 겁니까?
At the banquet assassination?
연회 암살에?
And the cliff kidnapping?
그리고 절벽에서의 납치 사건도요?
I was the master
내가 주작이었어
And he was just a pawn.
그리고 그는 단지 전당포였습니다.
It's true.
그것은 사실이다.
One person made some plans.
한 사람이 몇 가지 계획을 세웠어요.
Hoping to find the answer
답을 찾기를 바라면서
While the other waits at the foot of the cliff
다른 한 사람은 절벽 기슭에서 기다리는 동안
I believe you can win the heart of the person you love.
사랑하는 사람의 마음을 얻을 수 있다고 생각합니다.
How should I define you two?
너희 둘을 어떻게 정의해야 할까?
Is it funny or pathetic?
우스꽝스럽거나 한심합니까?
—Why... —Next time
—왜... —다음에
Be sure to refine your acting.
연기를 꼭 다듬으세요.
It's something that can't happen to someone.
누군가에게는 있을 수 없는 일이다
Shows no signs of shock or fear
충격이나 두려움의 징후를 나타내지 않음
When you wake up and find yourself
잠에서 깨어나 자신을 발견했을 때
Hanging over the edge of a cliff.
절벽 끝에 매달려 있습니다.
OK.
괜찮은.
If you want revenge, come to me.
복수하고 싶다면 나에게 와라.
Aren't you faithful to each other?
서로에게 충실하지 않습니까?
You're both competing for responsibility.
너희 둘 다 책임을 지기 위해 경쟁하고 있어
To yourself.
스스로에게.
Why does it sound like that?
왜 그런 소리가 나지?
Am I the villain this time too?
이번에도 내가 악당인가?
Has Jong Ye-ran become insignificant?
종예란이 하찮아졌는가
To you now?
지금 너한테?
you took him from me
당신은 나에게서 그를 가져갔습니다
And now you think I've let him down?
그런데 이제 내가 그를 실망시켰다고 생각하시나요?
Don't be a hypocrite.
위선자가 되지 마십시오.
I took him from you?
내가 그 사람을 당신에게서 빼앗았다고요?
I have made you his concubine.
내가 너를 그의 첩으로 삼았노라
And I took the initiative to get a divorce.
그리고 이혼을 위해 주도권을 잡았습니다.
What more do you want me to do?
내가 뭘 더 해주기를 바라나요?
Mu Yao, I thought you were smart.
Mu Yao, 나는 당신이 똑똑하다고 생각했습니다.
How could you be so stupid?
어떻게 그렇게 어리석을 수 있었나요?
Yes, I was foolish enough to think
그래요, 내가 생각할 만큼 어리석었어요
I could say that about him.
나는 그 사람을 그렇게 말할 수 있었다.
Haven't you tried it?
시도하지 않았나요?
To destroy everything I own?
내가 소유한 모든 것을 파괴하려고?
You succeeded.
당신은 성공했습니다.
He's starting to develop feelings for you.
그는 당신에 대한 감정을 키우기 시작했습니다.
How stupid I was
내가 얼마나 멍청했나봐
I lost to you before.
이전에 당신에게 졌다는 것입니다.
You are proud and selfish.
당신은 자랑스럽고 이기적입니다.
It's better to suffer
차라리 고통받는 게 낫지
than lose your dignity
존엄성을 잃는 것보다
You always blame others and blame yourself
당신은 항상 다른 사람을 비난하고 자신을 비난합니다
When things go wrong.
일이 잘못될 때.
Is Zhong Yeran the only person in this vast world?
이 광활한 세계에서 종예란은 유일한 사람인가?
Can't you live without that person?
그 사람 없이는 살 수 없나요?
What a small world you live in!
당신은 정말 작은 세상에 살고 있습니다!
Who are you to criticize me?
당신이 누구이기에 나를 비난하는가?
Wasn't it the same for you?
당신도 마찬가지 아니었나요?
Master, I led the painter's guards there.
스승님, 저는 화가의 경비병들을 그곳으로 이끌었습니다.
good.
좋은.
What should I do next?
다음에 무엇을 해야 합니까?
naught.
아무것도 아님.
All right.
알겠습니다.